<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Blogs on Daniel Brennand</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Daniel Brennand</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 20:33:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielbrennand.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fixing Proxmox USB Disconnects</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/proxmox-fix-usb-disconnect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 20:33:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/proxmox-fix-usb-disconnect/</guid><description>Towards the end of last year, I introduced Proxmox into my Homelab. I&amp;rsquo;m using it to host various services on VMs and LXC containers. In my setup, I have two external SSDs providing storage, these are connected to my Proxmox node via USB 3.0. However, recently I was experiencing issues with the SSDs suddenly disconnecting from the Proxmox node!
This was very frustrating because the VM filesystems that were on these SSDs were becoming corrupted!</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Google Workspace and Outlook Mail to iCloud+</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/google-outlook-to-icloud+/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 09:13:09 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/google-outlook-to-icloud+/</guid><description>Why I&amp;rsquo;m Migrating from Google Workspace and Outlook to iCloud+ Google Workspace My Google Workspace subscription is becoming increasingly more expensive 💰. The current price is £8.28 for the Business Standard plan, and next month this will be increasing to £9.20. This has become too expensive for me, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a cheaper alternative.
Outlook Mail I have an Outlook account which has been lying dormant for a long time now.</description></item><item><title>Build and Publish Container Images using GitHub Actions</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/build-and-publish-container-image-gha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 16:27:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/build-and-publish-container-image-gha/</guid><description>And we&amp;rsquo;re back! 👋
In this blog post we will be looking at building and publishing a container image to GitHub Packages using GitHub Actions!
I recently revisited an old project of mine; now called speeder. It&amp;rsquo;s a Python script to monitor your internet speed and send the results to InfluxDB. The results can then be visualised in Grafana. I originally created this script during the Coronavirus lockdowns whilst internet usage was high and essential for work.</description></item><item><title>Testing Ansible Content with Molecule</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/testing-ansible-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:14:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/testing-ansible-content/</guid><description>Time for another blog post! 🚀
In this blog post, I will be discussing how to test Ansible content with Molecule 🧪
What is Molecule? Molecule aids in the development and testing of Ansible content: collections, playbooks and roles.
github.com/ansible-community/molecule1 Why do we need to test Ansible content? Testing is an integral part of the software development lifecycle. It helps identify and prevent bugs from reaching production and in some cases, helps identify performance issues.</description></item><item><title>Managing Secrets in Ansible</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/managing-secrets-in-ansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 17:31:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/managing-secrets-in-ansible/</guid><description>Hi there! 👋
In my previous blog post I covered how to get started with Ansible. In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll be continuing to write about Ansible and covering how to manage secrets in Ansible playbooks.
Ready&amp;hellip; set&amp;hellip; go! 🚀
Managing Secrets in Ansible 🔑 As with most automation, we need to use credentials to authenticate to our servers and other applications. Examples of secrets include usernames and passwords, API keys, SSH keys, etc.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Ansible</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/getting-started-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 18:59:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/getting-started-ansible/</guid><description>Hey there! 👋
In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about Ansible. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for a little while now and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my experience with it and share some knowledge for others starting out! 🙂
Let&amp;rsquo;s begin! 🚀
What is Ansible? Ansible is an open-source automation tool which can be used to automate the management and configuration of servers and other devices. Written in Python, Ansible is agentless and connects over SSH.</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: Storing Credentials Securely</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/powershell-storing-credentials/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 23:39:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/powershell-storing-credentials/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on several PowerShell scripts that require credentials to access REST APIs. In this blog post, I will showcase two approaches for storing credentials securely for use in PowerShell scripts.
Encrypted Password File 🔒 The encrypted password file leverages the Windows Data Protection API (DPAPI) to encrypt the password as a System.Security.SecureString:
$Credentials = Get-Credential $Credentials.Password System.Security.SecureString $Credentials.Password | ConvertFrom-SecureString 01000000d08c9ddf0115d1118c7a00c04fc297eb01000000f5ab85d7ee9da048ae4ae797ee7eaf0a000000000200000000001066000000010000200000008c4a03d2f0731e0e7661d695fda8b441eaff31e75724931f31374a0c8292b636000000000e800000000200002000000028da885828bd627480178382ce9a1b477819e7703546ce41819d37f4e63d33ba20000000ab2c4401635ec24db9f20071e18dea0b79ce16ba38b5503ec9937b7fbc849dcf40000000155053a793c210998ef7317b0161e7344c2174b904b527c0cf24e7bbf2243b99e936df3ab67bc9e285a1be33aed37c7604fb07f5d0c44ceb7d6334ca30b0a610 By default DPAPI uses the current user context to generate an encryption key.</description></item><item><title>Using Git Hooks to lint PowerShell</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/git-hook-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 15:55:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/git-hook-powershell/</guid><description>Hi there! 👋
Recently I discovered Git Hooks. Git Hooks provide a way of running custom scripts when a certain git action occurs. In this post, I want to share a pre-commit Git Hook I&amp;rsquo;ve written to lint PowerShell code using the PSScriptAnalyzer module.
What is a Linter? 🕵️‍♂️ A linter analyses code to identify common errors, bugs and stylistic issues. Their aim is to improve code quality. Linters perform static analysis meaning they check code without executing it.</description></item><item><title>Use youtube-dl to download a streamed video</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/download-streamed-video/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 22:21:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/download-streamed-video/</guid><description>Hi there! 👋
In this blog post, I will show you how to download a streamed video from a website using youtube-dl.
Background Recently I needed to download a streamed video from a website for archival purposes. Full disclaimer, the service had already been paid for and I wanted to keep the video which was set to expire after a specific date.
Investigation 🔍 At first there was no obvious way to download the video.</description></item><item><title>Interacting with the ECS S3 API using the aws-sdk/client-s3 package</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/aws-sdk-s3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 10:13:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/aws-sdk-s3/</guid><description>Recently at work, a customer raised a ticket about programmatically interacting with UKCloud&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Storage service.
UKCloud&amp;rsquo;s Cloud Storage service is an object storage solution based on Dell EMC Elastic Cloud Storage (ECS). Access is via a RESTful API, which also provides support for Amazon&amp;rsquo;s S3 API.
UKCloud: Getting Started Guide for Cloud Storage 1 This ticket was interesting as the customer was using the @aws-sdk/client-s3 JavaScript package to upload images to the service.</description></item><item><title>Using Cloudflare as a Dynamic DNS (DDNS) provider</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/cloudflare-ddns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 18:13:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/cloudflare-ddns/</guid><description>How to use Cloudflare as a DDNS provider.</description></item><item><title>Create a blog for free using GitHub Pages and Hugo</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/blog-github-pages-hugo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 08:45:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/blog-github-pages-hugo/</guid><description>Welcome 👋
In this blog post, I will be showing you how to create a blog for free using GitHub Pages and Hugo.
I will walk you through the process of creating the GitHub repository (where your blog will live), creating your Hugo site, adding a theme to your blog 🎨, creating your first blog post and automating the publishing process!
What is GitHub Pages and Hugo? GitHub Pages allows you to create a website which is hosted directly from a repository on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>UK COVID-19 stats application</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/covid-19-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 13:56:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/covid-19-app/</guid><description>A simple Flask app showing how the COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) pandemic is developing in the UK.</description></item><item><title>Using Caddy v2's reverse proxy feature with a domain managed with Cloudflare!</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/caddy-cloudflare/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:08:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/caddy-cloudflare/</guid><description>How to use Caddy v2 as a reverse proxy with a Cloudflare managed domain.</description></item></channel></rss>