<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Meetup on Daniel Brennand</title><link>https://dbren.uk/tags/meetup/</link><description>Recent content in Meetup on Daniel Brennand</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 13:49:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dbren.uk/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ansible Meetup 5 June 2025</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-5-june/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 13:49:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-5-june/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was another great &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/ansible-london/events/307305041/">Ansible meetup&lt;/a> in London on the 5th June 2025. It was hosted at Metro Bank&amp;rsquo;s offices near Holburn and the attendance was excellent!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I gave a talk titled &lt;em>Ansible 101 - Getting Started on your Ansible Journey&lt;/em>. The talk was aimed at members of the community who&amp;rsquo;re new to Ansible and just starting their Ansible journey. We covered key terminology and concepts such as: Inventories, Playbooks, Modules and Plugins, Roles, Collections and Ansible Vault.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ansible Meetup 21 November 2024</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-21-november/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 18:46:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-21-november/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had an awesome time at the Ansible Meetup in London on the 21st of November 2024. The meetup was attended by around 25 people and was hosted at the Dell Technologies offices in London. The meetup was sponsored by Red Hat and Krameff Solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did my first ever talk at a meetup titled: &lt;em>Infrastructure as Code - VPS provisioning and configuration on Hetzner Cloud&lt;/em>. Hetzner is a public cloud provider I&amp;rsquo;ve used for personal projects and in my Homelab. I&amp;rsquo;ve been really impressed with their service and the value for money they offer. As part of my talk, I did a live demo of deploying a Virtual Private Server (VPS) and configuring a NGINX web server on the VPS using Ansible. The talk went really well and there was a some great Q&amp;amp;A with the audience &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>