<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Ansible on Daniel Brennand</title><link>https://dbren.uk/tags/ansible/</link><description>Recent content in Ansible on Daniel Brennand</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.146.7</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 20:34:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dbren.uk/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Becoming an Ansible Collection Maintainer: community.beszel</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-collections-community-beszel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 20:34:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-collections-community-beszel/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this blog post I wanted to talk about how I became a maintainer for the &lt;a href="https://github.com/ansible-collections/community.beszel">&lt;code>community.beszel&lt;/code>&lt;/a> Ansible Collection and my learnings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-beszel">What is Beszel?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://beszel.dev/">Beszel&lt;/a> is a simple, lightweight server monitoring software which can be self-hosted on your own infrastructure. I first heard about Beszel whilst reading the &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/selfhosted/comments/1eb4bi5/i_just_released_beszel_a_server_monitoring_hub/">&lt;code>/r/selfhosted&lt;/code>&lt;/a> subreddit about a year ago, and a couple of months ago I had time to deploy it in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/dbrennand/home-ops/tree/main/docker/beszel">Home-Ops&lt;/a> project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Beszel consists of two components: the hub and the agent. The hub provides a web interface for visualising the data sent from agents which run on your servers. My Beszel Hub is currently receiving data from 10 systems in my Homelab:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ansible Meetup 5 June 2025</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-5-june/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 13:49:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-5-june/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was another great &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/ansible-london/events/307305041/">Ansible meetup&lt;/a> in London on the 5th June 2025. It was hosted at Metro Bank&amp;rsquo;s offices near Holburn and the attendance was excellent!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I gave a talk titled &lt;em>Ansible 101 - Getting Started on your Ansible Journey&lt;/em>. The talk was aimed at members of the community who&amp;rsquo;re new to Ansible and just starting their Ansible journey. We covered key terminology and concepts such as: Inventories, Playbooks, Modules and Plugins, Roles, Collections and Ansible Vault.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Home-Ops | AWX and Ansible Execution Environments</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/homeops-ansible-ee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 15:08:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/homeops-ansible-ee/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey there folks! 👋&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Back again with another blog post! This time I wanted to discuss some cool changes I&amp;rsquo;ve made in my Homelab to explore AWX and Ansible Execution Environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-awx">What is AWX?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/ansible/awx">AWX&lt;/a> provides a web interface and REST API for managing and running Ansible content. AWX is the upstream project which Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s commerical offering Ansible Automation Platform&amp;rsquo;s Automation Controller is based on. AWX uses Execution Environments to run Ansible content and is deployed on Kubernetes using the &lt;a href="https://github.com/ansible/awx-operator">awx-operator&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ansible Meetup 21 November 2024</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-21-november/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 18:46:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/ansible-meetup-21-november/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had an awesome time at the Ansible Meetup in London on the 21st of November 2024. The meetup was attended by around 25 people and was hosted at the Dell Technologies offices in London. The meetup was sponsored by Red Hat and Krameff Solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I did my first ever talk at a meetup titled: &lt;em>Infrastructure as Code - VPS provisioning and configuration on Hetzner Cloud&lt;/em>. Hetzner is a public cloud provider I&amp;rsquo;ve used for personal projects and in my Homelab. I&amp;rsquo;ve been really impressed with their service and the value for money they offer. As part of my talk, I did a live demo of deploying a Virtual Private Server (VPS) and configuring a NGINX web server on the VPS using Ansible. The talk went really well and there was a some great Q&amp;amp;A with the audience &amp;#x1f604;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Testing Ansible Content with Molecule</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/testing-ansible-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:14:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/testing-ansible-content/</guid><description>&lt;p>Time for another blog post! &amp;#x1f680;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this blog post, I will be discussing how to test Ansible content with &lt;a href="https://github.com/ansible-community/molecule">Molecule&lt;/a> 🧪&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-molecule">What is Molecule?&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Molecule aids in the development and testing of Ansible content: collections, playbooks and roles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->github.com/ansible-community/molecule&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="why-do-we-need-to-test-ansible-content">Why do we need to test Ansible content?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Testing is an integral part of the software development lifecycle. It helps identify and prevent bugs from reaching production and in some cases, helps identify performance issues. When creating Ansible content we need to ensure that it works as expected and that we are not introducing any undesired behaviour. This is where Molecule comes in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Managing Secrets in Ansible</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/managing-secrets-in-ansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 17:31:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/managing-secrets-in-ansible/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi there! 👋&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my previous &lt;a href="https://danielbrennand.com/blog/getting-started-ansible/">blog post&lt;/a> I covered how to get started with Ansible. In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll be continuing to write about Ansible and covering how to manage secrets in Ansible playbooks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ready&amp;hellip; set&amp;hellip; go! 🚀&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="managing-secrets-in-ansible-">Managing Secrets in Ansible 🔑&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As with most automation, we need to use credentials to authenticate to our servers and other applications. Examples of secrets include usernames and passwords, API keys, SSH keys, etc. When using these types of secrets in playbooks, we need to store them securely but also still allow Ansible to access them when needed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with Ansible</title><link>https://dbren.uk/blog/getting-started-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 18:59:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dbren.uk/blog/getting-started-ansible/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey there! &amp;#x1f44b;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about Ansible. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for a little while now and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my experience with it and share some knowledge for others starting out! :slight_smile:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s begin! &amp;#x1f680;&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-ansible">What is Ansible?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Ansible is an open-source automation tool which can be used to automate the management and configuration of servers and other devices. Written in Python, Ansible is agentless and connects over SSH. Some common use-cases for Ansible include (but are not limited to):&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>