<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Ansible on Daniel Brennand</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/tags/ansible/</link><description>Recent content in Ansible on Daniel Brennand</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:14:50 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielbrennand.com/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Testing Ansible Content with Molecule</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/testing-ansible-content/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 16:14:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/testing-ansible-content/</guid><description>Time for another blog post! 🚀
In this blog post, I will be discussing how to test Ansible content with Molecule 🧪
What is Molecule? Molecule aids in the development and testing of Ansible content: collections, playbooks and roles.
github.com/ansible-community/molecule1 Why do we need to test Ansible content? Testing is an integral part of the software development lifecycle. It helps identify and prevent bugs from reaching production and in some cases, helps identify performance issues.</description></item><item><title>Managing Secrets in Ansible</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/managing-secrets-in-ansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 17:31:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/managing-secrets-in-ansible/</guid><description>Hi there! 👋
In my previous blog post I covered how to get started with Ansible. In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll be continuing to write about Ansible and covering how to manage secrets in Ansible playbooks.
Ready&amp;hellip; set&amp;hellip; go! 🚀
Managing Secrets in Ansible 🔑 As with most automation, we need to use credentials to authenticate to our servers and other applications. Examples of secrets include usernames and passwords, API keys, SSH keys, etc.</description></item><item><title>Getting started with Ansible</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/getting-started-ansible/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 18:59:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/getting-started-ansible/</guid><description>Hey there! 👋
In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about Ansible. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for a little while now and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my experience with it and share some knowledge for others starting out! 🙂
Let&amp;rsquo;s begin! 🚀
What is Ansible? Ansible is an open-source automation tool which can be used to automate the management and configuration of servers and other devices. Written in Python, Ansible is agentless and connects over SSH.</description></item></channel></rss>