<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>PowerShell on Daniel Brennand</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/tags/powershell/</link><description>Recent content in PowerShell on Daniel Brennand</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.119.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 23:39:10 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielbrennand.com/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PowerShell: Storing Credentials Securely</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/powershell-storing-credentials/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 23:39:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/powershell-storing-credentials/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on several PowerShell scripts that require credentials to access REST APIs. In this blog post, I will showcase two approaches for storing credentials securely for use in PowerShell scripts.
Encrypted Password File 🔒 The encrypted password file leverages the Windows Data Protection API (DPAPI) to encrypt the password as a System.Security.SecureString:
$Credentials = Get-Credential $Credentials.Password System.Security.SecureString $Credentials.Password | ConvertFrom-SecureString 01000000d08c9ddf0115d1118c7a00c04fc297eb01000000f5ab85d7ee9da048ae4ae797ee7eaf0a000000000200000000001066000000010000200000008c4a03d2f0731e0e7661d695fda8b441eaff31e75724931f31374a0c8292b636000000000e800000000200002000000028da885828bd627480178382ce9a1b477819e7703546ce41819d37f4e63d33ba20000000ab2c4401635ec24db9f20071e18dea0b79ce16ba38b5503ec9937b7fbc849dcf40000000155053a793c210998ef7317b0161e7344c2174b904b527c0cf24e7bbf2243b99e936df3ab67bc9e285a1be33aed37c7604fb07f5d0c44ceb7d6334ca30b0a610 By default DPAPI uses the current user context to generate an encryption key.</description></item><item><title>Using Git Hooks to lint PowerShell</title><link>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/git-hook-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 15:55:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://danielbrennand.com/blog/git-hook-powershell/</guid><description>Hi there! 👋
Recently I discovered Git Hooks. Git Hooks provide a way of running custom scripts when a certain git action occurs. In this post, I want to share a pre-commit Git Hook I&amp;rsquo;ve written to lint PowerShell code using the PSScriptAnalyzer module.
What is a Linter? 🕵️‍♂️ A linter analyses code to identify common errors, bugs and stylistic issues. Their aim is to improve code quality. Linters perform static analysis meaning they check code without executing it.</description></item></channel></rss>